when you think of v8-powered rear-wheel
drive full-size luxury sedans with all
the amenities you probably think of the
mercedes-benz s-class or the Audi a8 or
maybe the Lexus LS or the BMW 7-series
you don't think of Kia and yet this is a
brand new Kia k900 which is a v8 powered
rear-wheel drive full-size luxury sedan
with all the amenities and a $60,000
price tag this is a $60,000 luxury Kia
now that may not seem so strange to you
at first because I recently reviewed the
new Kia stinger' GT and that was a
$50,000 Kia but this is different for
two big reasons number one the Stinger
GT was a sporty car aimed at young
people and they're way more likely to
change their tastes and try a new brand
than older people the k900 is a luxury
car aimed at the kind of people who pay
with a personal check at the grocery
store the other reason this is different
from the Stinger is that this is a
luxury car luxury upscale high-end Sport
is not part of the equation here when I
think of Kia I think of those
commercials where hamsters are trying to
sell me a car
hamsters this is a $60,000 luxury car
from a brand who's best known
spokesperson is a rodent not
surprisingly this hasn't translated into
strong sales in the United States in
2017 Kia sold about 38 of these per
month in the entire country
by comparison mercedes sold about 1,500
s-class sedans per month in Canada in
2017 Kia sold seven of these not per
month seven total in the entire country
if you get one of these in Canada you
show up to a car show and you say you
get a Ferrari f40 yeah well I get
something even rarer a Canadian market
Kia k900 anyway rare weird and luxury
car seems right up my alley and so I
wanted to see what all the fuss was
about or at least with the limited
was about so today I'm going to show you
all of the interesting quirks and
features of the k900 and then I'm gonna
drive it and then I'm gonna give it a
dug score and I should mention I rented
this k900 here in Dallas at dallas-fort
Worth International Airport using Toro
which is this service that lets you rent
other peoples interesting and cool cars
instead of the same normal boring
airport rental cars you can sign up for
Toro using the link in the description
below and get $25 off your first rental
you can also check out the link in the
description below to see Toros app
anyway now on to the corpse
for the first clerk of this car I'm
gonna start with the name which I've
always found to be kind of ridiculous
Mercedes has the s550 Lexus has the LS
500 and he looked at those and they said
no no we can do better than that we're
gonna call it the k900 forget the LS 500
in the s550 this thing is 400 and better
it's like if a child named the car my
name is Jimmy and this is my card it's
the Jimmy J 10,000 also I'm sorry to
harp on the name but doesn't k900
kind of sound like a robotic dog from
the future I mean seriously you get
canine and this is the canine hundred
it's like sir we have developed the
canine hundred it can sniff treats from
a thousand miles away and it's also a
Kia next I'm moving under the hood I
mentioned before this has a v8 and
indeed it does they offer the k900 with
a v6 but this one has a 420 horsepower
five liter naturally aspirated v8 just
like a real full-size luxury sedan
that's pretty impressive from Kia
something I like about the v8 on the
plastic engine cover above the engine
kia has eight silver lines going out for
the middle of the engine just to really
drive home the point you got a v8 of
course nobody will ever notice that but
they did it anyway something else I like
under the hood is this little warning
label warning you not to come in contact
with the fan with your hand when the fan
is running take a look this label the
person's fingers have actually broken
off in the warning label the fan is cut
off the fingers it's a morbid warning
label I love it I only wish Kia added a
little blood that would really complete
things for me personal next I'm moving
on to the headlights I really loved the
look of the headlights in this car that
really look like the headlights you
expect in a luxury sedan look at that it
almost looks like too futuristic
soldiers marching together into battle
it's a cool look something I don't quite
like is on the fender that would be the
little fender vent on the side not only
is it sort of like a pathetic little
attempt at keeping up with the fender
vent trend but of course it's fake and
it dates the car and it looks stupid one
interesting item at the fender vendo you
see how it's sort of pinched in the
middle from the top and the bottom that
is supposed to mimic the look of the
Grill which kia calls the tiger nose
it's pinched on the top of the bottom
just like the grill and it's supposed to
sort of have a distinctive Kia look to
it next up another extra item I like on
this car that would be the mirror turn
signal so it's not just sort of some
turn signal slapped on the mirror but
instead it's this nice little C shape
that looks upscale and luxurious now
aside from that this cars exterior is
pretty conservative it's not really
designed to make a splash or make some
crazy statement so there aren't really
any other quirks so it's time to head
inside I'm gonna start with the door
panel now one interesting item you'll
notice in the door panel is this little
strip of LED lights down here now most
doors when they're open they have a
little reflector on the side and
oncoming traffic sees the reflector and
they know that a door is open they
should be careful but this car forgets
the reflector and it has these LEDs now
the weird thing about these LEDs is it's
a sort of little strip of LED dots that
look like they came out of a nightclub
or maybe an open sign outside of a Thai
restaurant they're so weird now when you
close the door the LEDs turn off when
you open them they turn back on another
interesting item inside the door panel
would be the power seat controls you
will see the bottom part of the seat
moves like normal and the middle part
the backrest also moves like normal
above the backrest there's the headrest
control with only one little problem
it's fixed the headrests in this car
moved manually not with the little
control on the door it's a fake headrest
control presumably there's some version
of this car with 28 weight power seats
and that headrest control is active but
in this car it just sits there looking
like it does something with actually
it's a fake control it has no purpose
but moving inside back to the lights for
a second one item I find absolutely
hilarious with the interior lights is
that the buttons to turn on the interior
lights don't say dome light or just
front and rear instead it says front
room and rear room and when you push
them front room that turns on the lights
for the front when you push the rear
room it turns on the lights for the back
I guess Kia doesn't like to think of it
as front seats this is the the front
room of the automobile next up another
interesting control in this car that
would be the center screen now if you
look at where the center screen is
placed you can see it looks like it
should be a touchscreen it's within
reach of the driver it'd be easy to
press but it isn't instead it's
controlled with a series of little
buttons in the center
console one thing Kia got absolutely
right in this car and gets right in all
their cars is the font kia has this cool
futuristic font and they use it in all
of the buttons and all of this switch
gear its distinctive and it looks cool
they even use in the infotainment system
and even the navigation system to show
street names and stuff
thoughts are an interesting thing a lot
of automakers will tell you off fonts
don't matter a button is a button and
nobody cares what it looks like but has
an apple proven that commercial design
is something people are actually
interested in Volvo also has a really
cool for all its buttons and it's gauges
and should be getting a Volvo you look
at that phone it just looks cool
whereas GM has been using the same
thoughts since like 1989 and every time
I get in a GM vehicle it doesn't matter
if it's a Corvette or an Escalade I
can't help but thinking it looks like my
grandma's 97 Buick Regal LS next up
another interesting item in the k900
this car has a panoramic sunroof that's
not all that surprising most cars at
this price point have one the unusual
thing is that most cars have like a
little buffer that separates the front
and the rear sunroof but this one
doesn't it's all just one big panel
which means that for those of us who are
interested in the little things we get
to watch the sunshade close together and
we can watch it meet in the middle in
perfect sun shade harmony it's actually
kind of a satisfying thing to watch when
it does meet also satisfying is the
sound of the k900 makes when you're
leaving it you turn off the car you're
about to get out and it makes the
following sound
I don't know why it has to make a sound
but it does and that's it next up we
move on to the glovebox which isn't
particularly unusual though it does
contain the owners manual which has a
few interesting peculiarities starting
with this little plastic sleeve that
it's in I guarantee the owner of the car
was never supposed to see the plastic
sleeve the owner's manual was supposed
to be delivered in this nice leather
pouch but I guess the dealer forgot to
remove it from the sleeve and the owner
of this card has never taken it out so
we get to see how kia keeps its owner's
manuals safe when the car is in transit
I especially like there's this little
Korean writing on the bottom of it
letting you know you're not in some
knockoff k900 this is the real deal now
when you actually take a look at the
owner's manual you'll notice a couple of
interesting things the one I noticed
right away is there's a loose page in
the owners manual figured it just came
out but if you look closely at the page
it actually says on it please see this
page instead of page three dash six and
three dash 14 in the owners manual in
other words this is like a supplement
they printed their owners manual wrong
and they want you to look at this
instead of something else now I looked
at pages 3 - 6 and 3 - 14 the forbidden
pages and what I found is that actually
they kind of talked about different
stuff I don't really understand why this
is supposed to replace those pages and
it doesn't seem to have to do with
equipment there are items all over the
owners manual that say if applicable for
features that some models have and some
don't
nonetheless I guess Kia decided this
page was better than some of these pages
it's really strange I've never seen an
addendum added to an owner's manual in
this fashion before now speaking of the
owner's manual I should mention that it
is absolutely massively massive it's
just huge it's one of the biggest I've
ever come across in fact it's so big
that I strongly suspect that they didn't
really go to the trouble of reading the
entire thing I did read some of the
owner's manual
I've found a couple of interesting
errors for example on page 4 - 44 under
the horn section it says to sound the
horn press the horn symbol on your
steering wheel check the horn regularly
to be sure it operates properly then the
next line to sound the horn press the
horn area indicated by the horn symbol
on your steering wheel
okay so thanks for telling me that twice
then the rest of the page is blank so
really this is a high-quality document
and I would trust it to have every piece
of information I could possibly need oh
and by the way one other item about that
horn page it specifically says you have
to press the horn symbol on your
steering wheel for the horn top right it
says the horn will only operate when
this area is pressed
next up we move on to the screens now
there aren't as many configurable and
interesting features inside this cars
there on the stinger GT or the Genesis
g90 but there are a couple of quirks
starting with the gauge cluster screen I
really like the fact that you could
adjust the service interval in this car
if you don't want the service interval
to say 5,000 miles say your oil change
light comes on we could say forget that
let's make it 8,000 miles then you can
just keep driving with all the peace of
mind that that entails next up moving on
to the infotainment system settings
there are a couple of interesting quirks
in here one of which is that in the
navigation system settings you can
actually change the color of your route
guidance line the little line that tells
you make a left turn on this street make
a right turn on this on-ramp you can
make it various different colors
depending on your preference I've seen a
lot of different things that are
configurable before but I've never seen
that who looks at the route guidance
line and says boy I wish that were
purple another interesting configurable
item in the voice recognition system you
can choose between normal and expert so
if you feel that you're a voice
recognition system expert you can tell
the car that you know how some people
brag that they're good at video games
and others brag they're good at driving
or whatever maybe some people go around
telling their co-workers yeah I'm a
voice recognition expert no problem yeah
I'm an expert at voice recognition
systems I know you're just an amateur
you'd have it on normal I have an expert
no big deal yeah another interesting
piece of configurability there is an
option to choose the image that is
displayed we have power off the default
is no image but you can also choose a
Kia ad image I don't know why anybody
would do that or you can choose a custom
image so if you want like a picture of
your kids to show up on the infotainment
screen if you have the screen turned off
you can upload one it actually
have it up there I've never actually
seen that before in any other car it's
kind of a cool idea
next up back to the navigation settings
one interesting item I found if you go
into guidance you have two options curve
and merge yeah I want curve and merge
guidance fortunately they're both
checked so I will be guided to curves
and merges I don't know why those are
options I don't know what happens if you
uncheck them I don't know what they do
but I bet I could find out in that
900-page owner's manual and one other
thing I absolutely love about the
infotainment system is the little
interactive guide that teaches you how
to use the system if you click on it a
little box pops up that says we will
learn about ways to use this system
who's we
me and the car me and I don't know but
we will learn and we will learn if you
go through it the system does have an
interactive guide that teaches you how
to use it and at the end it pops up a
little box that says congratulations you
have finished learning about the system
oh it's like my birthday congratulations
to me I figured out the infotainment
system in the k900 here's one thing I
haven't figured out there's this huge
screen to display the artist of the song
name whatever but they only use about an
inch of it so it just sort of Scrolls
through a little at a time hey keya why
not just display it all at once in the
remaining 10 inches of the screen and
finally we move on to the back seat
which is supremely roomy and comfortable
it's obviously very large back here this
is after all a full-size luxury sedan
and there are a couple of quirks in back
most of which are centered around the
center armrest now obviously you can put
it up and then it goes away and you fit
three people back here or you can put it
down you'll see a couple of cup holders
right here but the most interesting
pieces are along here now if you take a
close look here you will find seven
total buttons and they're all kind of
interesting the outer two buttons are
fairly standard there the heated seat
buttons for the rear seats that's pretty
cool but most luxury cars have that the
weirdest button back here by far is on
the left that it says rear lock and
that's the button you push to lock the
rear climate control except you're
sitting in the back seat
that button should be in the front and
in fact the front seat passengers can
lock the rear climate control but why do
the rear seat passengers have the
ability to lock their own climate
control especially because if they want
to unlock it all they have to do is just
press the rear lock button again I have
no idea why there's a rear climate lock
button in the rear seats accessible to
the rear passengers never seen this
before it makes no sense now next to the
rear lock button that would be the power
rear sunshade button you push it and
then the rear sunshade whirs into place
just like in so many luxury cars that's
not all that uncommon anymore also not
uncommon is the fact that this car has
sun shades on the doors very cool but in
this car they aren't power operated like
they are in Mercedes BMWs instead you
have to manually put them in place Oh
can't even believe it almost this is
supposed to be a luxury car what the
k900 redeems its luxury car status with
a couple little buttons on the right
side of the rear center controls those
be the buttons to control the front seat
if you're sitting back here on the
passenger side you can move the front
passenger seat forward to give yourself
extra legroom that's for all the people
who are being chauffeured around in
their k900 the other interesting button
in these rear seat controls that would
be the one in the middle it is marked
k900 now this isn't actually a button if
you press it it does nothing but you can
sit there and look at it and you can
push it if you want just to remind
yourself that you are swathed in Kia's
finest luxury automobile now another
interesting thing back here a very
strange feature I've never seen in any
other car that would be the door locks
and if you want to unlock the doors you
can just reach up you can pull the lock
and that unlocks it you want to lock it
you reach up you push the lock and then
the door is locked it seems simple
enough but if you go down to the door
panel about four inches down from there
you will see a little lock and unlock
button now in a lot of luxury cars that
button lets you lock and unlock all the
doors because if you're the chauffeur
driven passenger you should have control
over whether the doors are locked and
unlocked but in the k900 that button
only controls your door
so you can lock and unlock the door
manually or 4 inches down from there you
can lock and unlock the door by pushing
a button and that button has no effect
on the other doors in the k900
so you have two different options for
locking and unlocking your door in the
k900 both within six inches of each
other so those are the courts and
features of the k900 and now it's time
to get behind the wheel for more of my
thoughts on the k900 click the link
below to visit autotrader.com slash
oversteer why I'm driving the k900 I've
been driving this car around Dallas for
a couple days I have a pretty good idea
of what's going on with it
now one thing I have to admit about this
car I'm a little bit disappointed with
the level of equipment which is
surprising because this cars whole play
is its value its it gives you so much
for so little compared to the rivals but
here's the thing there's no heads-up
display you already saw that thing with
the weird headrest on the door there's
no touchscreen there's no bi-xenon
headlights
there's just single Zeeland there's no
auto steer this car actually has it
doesn't quite have the level of
equipment that I want the seats in back
aren't ventilated I mean I can kind of
go through it there's no 360 degree
camera in fact which every luxury car
has now especially one that costs 60
grand I was kind of thinking this would
be like an s-class in terms of equipment
but it would just sort of be you know
it's cheaper because it's a Kia and
people aren't paying the money for the
brand name but this car isn't even on
s-class level in terms of equipment and
it costs like an eClass and it's
actually equipped like one too so why
would anyone buy this over an eClass
when the price point is the same and the
equipment is the same and the difference
is this one has the Kia brand name I
mean you wouldn't it be ridiculous so
that's actually been kind of a
surprising disappointment at this car I
thought I'd be sitting in here and
thinking oh my god this thing is like an
s-class but it's just as a Kia badge and
if you're willing to spend half the
money you know and and put away the
badge notoriety it won't matter it's not
quite like that now with that said it
does have a lot of equipment I mean
there's a lot of luxury stuff in here
moving the front seat
and all that that's pretty impressive
but it it doesn't go above and beyond I
think it sort of meets the expectations
now with that said it's it's interesting
I was expecting a little bit more
features equipment whatever I was
expecting the drive to be worse than it
is
I actually love how this car drives it's
tremendously smooth really just really
really smooth the engine has a ton of
power and here's something that really
surprised me much more than I thought
this car is very stable I came into
Dallas the other night and it was
storming and was just pouring in
thunderstorms the guy who I rented this
car from he told me was the worst lungs
he's ever seen in Dallas my flight was
four hours delayed I was driving it
after I picked it up and it just felt
rock solid and stable on the highway
almost on the level of an eClass or an
s-class and I was really surprised about
that I was going speeds I probably
should have been going given the weather
and the car was like planted and it felt
like I could have just kept going and
going even higher speeds that's not
something I'm usually used to from an
Asian car typically it's the German cars
because they're built for the Autobahn
that have that sort of high speed
capability but this thing just felt
rock-solid at higher speeds even in bad
weather which was impressive to me and I
love how the v8 feels
I mean I'm into turbo cars the whole
thing but I think the thing I'm gonna
miss the most everybody talks about I
don't want all this tech I don't want
all these features that drive for me I'm
ready for all that what I'm not ready
for has given up v8 this car is great
proof of why you don't want to give up a
v8 the v8 is smooth it's powerful it's
got torque it's not loud it just feels
so good the only thing you can't do is
get thirty miles per gallon it's just a
very comfortable ride not much noise
gets into the cabin they've done a
really great job with that with making
this car feel like the luxury car that
it is and even feel like sort of the
German luxury car that it is at higher
speeds on the highway which surprised me
a lot
but I just wished that there were maybe
a few more features I mean how do you
not have a 360 camera come on you're
telling people the old features is what
we got we got value well show me I mean
where where some of the stuff and so
that's the Kia k900 the kia luxury sedan
this thing is a complete failure kia has
staked its entire existence on selling
cheap cars to millennials cars whose
price tags end in 995 so they seemed
cheaper than they actually are and they
want to try to make a luxury sedan gia
has no business making a vehicle in this
segment and I can't believe they sell
this here then again I probably would
have said the same thing about Toyota
before they came out with Lexus and I
have to admit it's an even better value
if you buy one used of course that's
assuming that you can find one of the 12
they sold in your local area anyway now
it's time for the dugs score starting
with the weekend categories and styling
the k900 is fine only fine not great and
not bad and it gets a 5 out of 10
acceleration does 0 to 60 in 5.5 seconds
which gives it a 5 out of 10
handling is acceptable certainly not
unstable but steering is lightened snow
sports car and it gets a 4 out of 10
cool factor isn't very high but even
though it doesn't have a Mercedes badge
it's still an expensive somewhat cool
car and it gets a 4 out of 10 importance
is low this car is important only in
this sense that it shows kia wants to
make luxury cars but it hasn't exactly
made a splash and it gets a 3 out of 10
bringing the total weekend score to 21
out of 50 next up for the daily
categories starting with features the
k900 is reasonably well equipped but
it's missing some important stuff and it
gets only a 6 out of 10 comfort is good
the ride is nice and the car is smooth
and it gets a 7 out of 10
quality is good the interior is pretty
nice and I expect it to be reliable and
it gets a 7 out of 10
practicality is only OK the 16 cubic
feet of cargo space gives it a 5 out of
finally there's value and I just don't
see it it's an OK car for 60 grand but
not better and it gets only a 5 out of
10 bringing the total daily score to 30
out of 50 add it all up and the Doug
score is 51 out of 100 and here's how it
compares to some other luxury sedans
either of
of course it's nowhere near the same
price point as some of them but it is
close on price to others and regardless
its way behind the pack the k900 is a
car best bought used for a huge discount
[Music]